Guide to the World War I Pamphlet Collection 1901-1944 (bulk 1914-1919)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Germany - Domestic Politics: Employment (in German), 1917-1919; Wirkungen der Kriegsziele unserer Gegner auf die Arbeitslơhne in Deutschland. Berlin: Kriegspresseamt, 1917. (extremely fragile); Krieg und Arbeiterschaft: sechs Aufsätze aus der Deutschen kriegswochenschau, mit 5 Abbildungen. Berlin: Linden-Druckerei, 1918.; Braun, Adolf. Der Ententefrieden und die Arbeiterklasse. Berlin: Buchh. Vorwärts, 1919. (Box-folder 12/8)
- Germany - Domestic Politics: Peace Concerns (in German), 1915-1916; Rotheit, Rudolf. Die Friedens bedingungen der deutschen Presse: Llos von Reuter und Havas. Berlin: Puttkammer & Muhlbrecht, 1915.; Michaelis. Die Vorgeschichte des Weltkrieges. Oldenburg: Gerhard Stalling, 1916. (Box-folder 12/9)
- Germany - Domestic Politics: Peace Concerns (in German), 1917-1918; Lehmann, J. F. Deutschlands Zukunft bei einem guten und bei einem schlechten Frieden. München: J.F. Lehmann, 1917.; Müller-Meiningen, Ernst. Der Reichstag und der Friedenschluss: Beiträge zur Friedensresolution, dem "Selbstbestimmungsrecht der Völker". München: Duncker & Humbolt, 1918. (Box-folder 12/10)
- Germany - Domestic Politics: Provinces (in German), 1915-1918; Metz. Jubaliden ausiedlung in der Provinz Sachsen. 1915.; Die Neuordnung unserer östlichen Nachbargebiete: Ansprachen und Reden auf der Versammlung des "Unabhängigen Ausschusses für einen Deutschen Frieden". Berlin: Unabhängiger Ausschuss für einen Dt. Frieden, 1918. (2 copies) (Box-folder 12/11)
- Germany - Domestic Politics: Provinces (in German), 1922; Besatzungswahnsinn am deutschen Rhein. Berlin: Hans Robert Engelmann, 1922. (Box-folder 12/12)
- Germany - Economics and Finance (in English), 1915-1917 and undated; Helfferich, Karl. The Third German War Loan Speech Made ... in the Reichstag on August 20th. Berlin:; Disconto-Gesellschaft (Berlin, Germany). Economic Life in Germany During the War: Supplement, October 1915. Berlin: Disconto-Gesellschaft, 1915.; Economic Collapse of German Credit & Rates of Exchange on London & Berlin, as quoted in Amsterdam (expressed in percentage). 1917. (Box-folder 12/13)
- Germany - Economics and Finance (in English and German), 1902-1917 and undated; Bastian, Finanzrat. Die Verwaltung von Wertpapieren. Berlin: n.d.; Fried, Alfred H. Die Grundlagen der modernen Wirtschaft und der Krieg. Esslingen a. N: Langguth, 1902.; Nach 1000 Tagen Allgemeine Weltwirtschafts-Richtlinien als allgmeines Kriegsziel und der nahende Friede. Zürich: Orell Füssli, 1917.; Meesmann, P. Der Kriegsausgang und die deutsche Industrie. 1917. (Box-folder 12/14)
- Germany - Foreign Politics (in Danish, English, French, Italian and Spanish), 1914; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. Rigskansler [Theobald] v. Bethmann Hollwegs Tale i den tyske Rigsdags Møde den 2. December 1914. 1914.; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. Speech made by the Imperial Chancellor von Bethmann Hollweg in the Reichstag on December 2, 1914. 1914.; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. Discours du Chancelier de l'Empire. Seance du Reichstag du 2 decembre 1914. 1914. (2 copies); Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. Discorso del Cancelliere dell'Impero, nella seduta del Reichstag del 2 Dicembre 1914. 1914.; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. El Canciller del Imperio Dr. v. Bethmann Hollweg, ha pronunciado el siguiente discurso en el Congreso el 2 de diciembre en la segunda sesión de Guerra. [s. l.]: [s. n.], 1915. (2 copies) (Box-folder 12/15)
- Germany - Foreign Politics (in English), 1914 and undated; Germany. The German White Book with important official addenda: Documents anent, the outbreak of the European war. (Only Authorized Translation). New York City: The Fatherland, 1914.; Imperial German Foreign Office. Documents relating to the Outbreak of the War. n.d. (Box-folder 12/16)
- Germany - Foreign Politics (in German), 1914-1919; Amtliche Aktenstücke zur Vorgeschichte des Krieges. 1914.; Ruete, Rudolph Said-. Vaterland und Heimat: Ein Problem des Weltbürgertums und der Verständigung. Zurich: Art. Institut Orell Fussli, 1917.; Witting, Richard. Auswärtige Politik und Diplomatenkunst, Kriegsmentalität, Lehmann und Krause. Flugschriften des Berliner Tageblatt, [Hft. I]. Berlin: Kronen-Verlag g.m.b.h, 1917.; Stimmen über die Kriegslage und Kriegsziele. 1916. (German government's vote on the war situation and war targets.); Kautsky, Karl and Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands. Annehmen oder Ablehnen?: Die Unabhängige Sozialdemokratie und der Friede. Berlin: Verlagsgenossenschaft "Freiheit", 1919.; Soetbeer, Heinrich. Einfluss des krieges auf verträge zwischen angehörigen der kriegführenden staaten: Vortrag gehalten an 18. märz 1914 in der vollversammlung des Deutschen handelstags. Berlin: Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914. (Box-folder 13/1)
- Germany - Foreign Politics (in Italian), 1914; Documenti Ufficiali Sulle Cause Della Guerra Del 1914. Frankfurt am Main: J. Baer & co, 1914. (Box-folder 13/2)
- Germany - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in English), 1923; Kaufmann, Karl J. Danzig's German Character and National Independence and Its Importance in the Past: Documentary Evidence from the Danzig City Archives. Danzig?, 1923. (13/3)
- Germany - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in German), 1915-1917 and undated; Oberschlesiens Schiksalsftunde. n.d. (extremely fragile); Studnicki, Władysław. Die umgestaltung Mittel-Europa's durch den gegenwärtigen krieg. Die Polen-frage in ihrer internationalen bedeutung. Wien: H. Goldschmiedt ges. m.b.h, 1915.; Boehm, Mac Hildebert. Die krisis des deutschbaltischen Menschen. Berlin: Grenzboten, 1915.; Gaigalat. Die litauisch-baltische Frage. 1915.; Zimmermann, Emil. Kann uns Mesopotamien eigene Kolonien ersetzen? Berlin: Kolonial-Wirtschaftl. Komittee, 1917. (Box-folder 13/4)
- Germany - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in German), 1918-1923; Cleinow, Georg. Die Polenfrage Vor Der Entscheidung. Berlin: Grenzboten, 1918.; Ebner, Arno. Die Rechtswirkungen der feindlichen Besetzung auf die Bevölkerung des besetzten Gebiets. Leipzig: [s.n.], 1919.; Masing, Oskar. Baltisches Deutsch: 1; Aus der Arbeit am Deutschbaltischen Dialektwörterbuch; 2 ;O. Masing. Überreicht von der Gesellschaft für Altertumskunde zu Riga.(Leipzig): (Teubner), 1923. (Doctoral Dissertation) (Box-folder 13/5)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: American-German (in German), 1914-1918 and undated; The League of Truth. An Appeal to All Friends of Truth. Berlin: The League of Truth, n. d. (2 copies); Franzer, Berthold. Die Amesrikanischen Kriegslieferungen und Wir. Hamburg: Gebruder Paustian, 1915.; Die Strafe Amerikas. Berlin, Leipzig, 1916. (a Pamphlet on the Attitude of the United States in the European War); Deutsch-amerikanische Sympathie-Kundgebung: Im Berliner Rathaus Am 11. August 1914 = German-American Meeting of Sympathy: in the Berlin City Hall, August 11, 1914. Berlin: Druck: Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914.; Committee. England's Perfidy Exposed by Americans. Munich: 1914.; Hobson-Kraus, Katherine Thayer. To the People and Press of America. Dresden: 1914.; Rains, Leon. Letter. Dresden: 1914. (2 copies); McAndrew, James W. Betreffs: Behandlung der Kriegsgefangenen. France: 1918. (not a part of the original Library of Congress gift) (letter from General Pershing urging the Germans to surrender and promising fair treatment to POWs) (Box-folder 13/6)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Anglo-German (in English), 1914-1915; England's Complicity in the Great War: An Examination of Official Documents and of English Documents in Particular. Berlin: Printed by Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914.; Schulze-Gaevernitz, Gerhard von. How England Looks to Germany. New York: The Laureate press, 1915. (2 copies); Who Broke the Peace of Europe? Translated from German & Dutch Reports. 1914. (2 copies) (Box-folder 13/7)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Anglo-German (in French), 1915; L'angleterre Et Sa Complicité Dans La Guerre Actuelle D'après Les Publications Officielles Et Principalement D'après Les Documents Anglais. Berlin, 1915. (Box-folder 13/8)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Anglo-German (in German), 1914-1916; Peez, Alexander von. England und der Kontinent. Wien: C. Fromme, 1915.; Englands Mitschuld am Weltkriege: eine Prüfung der amtlichen Veröffentlichungen, besonders der englischen Aktenstucke. Berlin: Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914. (2 copies); Wislicenus, Paul, and Curt Trützschler von Falkenstein. England und der Weltkrieg: Betrachtungen über die Volksseele. Darmstadt: Falken-Verl, 1916. (Box-folder 13/9)
- Foreign Relations: Austro-German (in German), 1915; Liebesgaben aus dem Deutschen Reiche. Wien: Fromme, 1915. (Box-folder 13/10)
- Foreign Relations: Austro-German (in German), 1919-1920; Christ, Alfred. Deutschland, wir kommen! Stimmen aus dem geistigen Deutsch-Österreich für den Anschluss an Deutschland. Halle (Saale): R. Mühlmann, 1919.; Horsetzkn, Ernst. Die vier letzten Kriegswochen (24 Oktober bis 21, November 1918). Vien: Karl Harbauer, 1920. (Box-folder 13/11)
- Germany - Foreign Relations in English: Belgo-German (in English), 1914-1917 and undated; Bissing, Moritz. General Von Bissing's Testament: A Study in German Ideals. London: T.F. Unwin Ltd, 1917.; The Breach of Belgian Neutrality by England & Belgium. 1914.; Claussen, M. B. Belgium's Pact with England. Hew York: German Information Service, n. d.; Major Bauer and Dr. Wagner. The Belgium People's War, carried on contrary to International Law. Translation. Berlin: Military Department for the Investigation of Breaches of the Rules of War, 1915. (Box-folder 13/12)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Belgo-German (in French), 1914-1915 and undated; L'Angleterre et la Belgique violatrices de la neutralité belge. 1914.; L'Accusation et la défense. Rotterdam: 1915.; La Neutralite Belge. Berlin: Stilke, Georg, n. d. (Box-folder 13/13)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Belgo-German (in German), 1914-1915; Kronseder, Otto. Brüssel vom kulturgeschichtlichen Standpunkte. Belgien in geographischer Hinsicht. Erlangen: A. Deichert, 1915.; Die Belgische Neutralitat. Berlin: G. Stilke, 1915. (2 copies); Daenell, E. Die Mitschuld Belgiens am Weltkrieg. 1914. (Box-folder 13/14)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Franco-German (in English and French), 1914-1922; Germany. French Industry in the Occupied Districts. Munich: Press of R. Oldenburg [!], 1916. (2 copies); Violation of the Geneva Convention of July 6. 1906 by French Troops and Franctireurs. 1914. (2 copies); William, and George. How the Franco-German Conflict Might Have Been Avoided.: Official Documents Published by the German Government. Berlin: Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914. (2 copies); Schneider, Otto C. Truth Must Prevail: Historical Relations of France and Germany. Munchen: Knorr & Hirth, 1922.; Comment la guerre franco-allemande aurait pu être évitée. 1914. Berlin: 1914. (Box-folder 14/1)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Franco-German (in German and Italian), 1914-1923; Beiträge zur Naturgeschichte des Krieges. Lille. Berlin: H.R. Engelmann, 1920.; Keller-Huguenin, E. Zum Krieg in Frankreich. Krieg! Ruckzug, Stellungs-Krieg. Zurich: Rascher & Co., 1914.; Reiderer, Heinrich. Frankreich-Freiheit und Friede? Berlin: Deutsche Verlagsgesellschaft für Politik und Geschichte, 1923.; Verletzung der Genfer Konvention vom 6. Juli 1906 durch Franzosische Truppen und Freischarler. Berlin: 1914.; Come Si Sarebbe Potuto Evitare La Guerra Tra La Francia E La Germania: Documenti Ufficiali Del Governo Germanico. Berlin: s.n., 1914. (Box-folder 14/2)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: French Black Colonial Troops (in Dutch, English, French and German), 1915-1920; Het Gebruik Van Kleurlingentroepen, in Strijd Met Het Volkenrecht, Op Het Oorlogsveld in Europa Door Engeland En Frankrijk. Berlijn: s.n., 1915. (Translates as: The violation of international law from England and France by the use of colored troops in the theater of war in Europe.); Morel, E. D. The Horror on the Rhine. London: Union of Democratic Control, 1920.; Germany. La violation du droit des gens de la part de l'Angleterre et de la France par l'emploi de troupes de couleur sur le théâtre de la guerre en Europe. Berlin: s.n, 1915. (Translates as: The violation of international law from England and France by the use of colored troops in the theater of war in Europe.); Germany. Bolkerrechtswidrige Berwendung farbiger Gruppen auf dem europaischen kriegsschauplatz durch England und Frankreich. Berlin, 1915. (Translates as: The violation of international law from England and France by the use of colored troops in the theater of war in Europe.) (Box-folder 14/3)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Russo-German (in English), 1914; Germany. The German White-Book (Only Authorized Translation) How Russia and Her Ruler Betrayed Germany's Confidence and Thereby Caused the European War, with the Original Telegrams and Notes. Berlin: Liebheit & Thiesen, 1914. (2 copies) (Box-folder 14/4)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: Russo-German (in German), 1915-1918; "Germanicus": Das russische Gespenst. 1915.; Politics...Germany: Germania, March 12, 1918. Germany: 1918. (six half-pages of a letter typed on yellow carbon paper with edits. no author) (Box-folder 14/5)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with the Central Powers (in German), 1914-1915; Kriegs-Depeschen 1914, Vierter Monat (November). Berlin: Boll und Pickardt, 1914. (serial publication); Der Kriegsverlauf: Sammlung der amtlichen Nachrichten von den Kriegsschauplatzen. Berlin: Carl Heymanns, 1915. (Box-folder 14/6)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with the Central Powers (in German), 1918; Central Powers (1914-1918), and Ukraine. Anlagen der Denkschrift zu dem Friedensvertrag zwischen Deutschland, Österreich-Ungarn, Bulgarien und der Türkei einerseits und der Ukrainischen Volksrepublik andererseits sowie zu dem deutsch-ukrainischen Zusatzvertrag. Berlin: Carl Heymanns, 1918. (2 copies) (Box-folder 14/7)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with the Entente (in English), 1915; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. The Triple Entente: Ten years of its policy. Berlin: S. Preuss, 1915. (Box-folder 14/8)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with the Entente (in German), 1915-1916 and undated; Harms, Bernhard. Die Gegner und wir im Spiegel der Kriegslage. Berlin: Kriegs-Presse-Amt, n.d.; Bethmann Hollweg, Theobald von. Zehn Jahre Ententepolitik. Zur Vorgeschichte des Krieges. Rede des deutschen Reichskanzlers vom 19. August 1915. Berlin: G. Stilke, 1915.; J'accuse! Aus den Aufzeichnungen eines feldgrauen Akademikers. Berlin: Stilke, 1915. (there is a response to this book located in Switzerland literature); Neumann, Josef. Die Zerschmetterung Deutschlands: Die Kriegsziele unserer Feinde im Spiegel ihrer eignen Äusserungen; Im Auftr. d. Auskunftsstelle Vereinigter Verbände. Berlin: Curtius, 1915.; Falsche propheten: ein rückblick auf die stimmungsmache der Entente im herbst und winter 1914/15. Stuttgart: Deutsche verlags-anstalt, 1916.; Hönn, Karl. Deutschland im europäischen Kriege. St.Gallen: Beck & Co, 1916. (Box-folder 14/9)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with the Entente (in German), 1917-1926; von Hollweg, Bethmann. Weissbuch, [enthaltend] eine Zusammenstellung der Vereinbarungen zwischen Deutschland und den feindlichen Staaten über die beiderseitigen Kriegs- u. Zivilgefangenen: Reichstag; 13. Legislatur-Periode; 2. Session 1914/17; Nr 645. Berlin: C. Heymann, 1917.; Fendrich, Anton. Ein Wort an die unten und die oben. Stuttgart: Franckh, 1918.; Stieve, Friedrich. Wie Frankreich und Russland zum Weltkrieg kamen. München: O. Gross, 1926. (Box-folder 14/10)
- Germany - Foreign Relations: with Neutral Countries (in German), 1918; Auslandsstelle des kriegspresseamts. Die behandlung der neutralen durch den verband im vierten kriegsjahr. Berlin: Druck der Norddeutschen buchdruckerei, 1918. (Box-folder 14/11)
- Germany - Military (in German), 1914-1915; Forster, Paul. Vorwarts und durch!: Ein Kriegsruf. Berlin: Gsellius, 1914.; Impertro, M. Unser Hindenburg: Sein Leben u. seine Taten. Dresden-A.: Mignon-Verl, 1915.; Oer, P. Seb. V. Feldbrief 1: ein Feldzug der Luge. Coln Mainz: St Joseph Müller, 1915. (serial publication) (2 copies); Beck, Josef. Feldbrief: 2. Wie erzieht man Soldaten? Coln: St. Josephs-Verein, 1915. (serial publication); Oer, Sebastian von. Feldbrief: 3. Wie lange noch? Coln: St. Josephs-Ver, 1915. (serial publication); Frick, Wilhelm, Ludwig Finckh, Auguste Supper, A. Doerrfuss, and Hermann Hesse. Zum Sieg; ein Brevier für den Feldzug. Stuttgart: Die Lese, 1915.; Germany. Kriegs-Gesetze und -Verordnungen 1914. M. Gladbach: Volksvereins-Verlag, 1915. (part of a periodical) (Box-folder 14/12)
- Germany - Military (in German), 1917; Ins vierte Kriegsjahr: Ruck- u. Ausblicke an d. Schwelle des 4. Kriegsjahres nebst 225 Original-Beitragen fuhrender Manner Deutschlands u. seiner Verbundeten. Breslau: Siwinna, 1917. (Box-folder 14/13)
- Germany - Military (in German), 1917-1923; Der Krieg im August 1917. 1917. (extremely fragile; part of a periodical series); Der Krieg im Februar 1918. 1918. (extremely fragile; part of a periodical series); Bloch, Ernst. Schadet oder nutzt Deutschland eine niederlage seiner militars? Bern: Der Freie Verlag, 1918.; Zwehl, Hans von. Generalstabsdienst im Frieden und im Kriege. Berlin: E.S. Mittler & Sohn, 1923. (Box-folder 15/1)
- Germany - Military (in Italian), 1918; Santamaria, Pietro. Appetiti Dei Pangermanisti. Rome: Tipo-grafia Ausonia, 1918.(German pamphlet translated into Italian) (Box-folder 15/2)
- Germany - Military: Campaigns / Battles (in German), 1914-1915; Krieges, Kalender und Krieges, Depeschen: Nach den amtlichen berichten. Berlin: Deutsches Berlagshaus Bong & Co., 1914. (fragile); Moser. Kampf und siegestage 1914. Berlin: Ernst Siegfried Mittler & Sohn, 1915.; Pawlowski, Eduard. Tilsit unter russischer herrschaft, 26. august bis 12. september 1914. Tilsit, Ostpr: E. Pawlowski, 1915. (Box-folder 15/3)
- Germany - Military: Campaigns / Battles (in German), 1916; Die Champagne-Herbstschlacht 1915. 1916. (2 copies) (Box-folder 15/4)
- Germany - Military: Campaigns / Battles (in German), 1917-1921 and undated; Die Halberstaedter in der Flandernschlacht. n.d.; Vier Jahre Verteidigungs-kampf. Berlin: Karl Curtius, n.d.; Hahn, v. Mein Regiment in Den Kampfen Vor Verdun Und an Der Somme Im Jahre 1916; Hahn, V., Major U. Reg.-Kommandeur; Zur Feier D. 2. Stiftungstages D. Regiments Am 6. Marz 1917 Im Felde. Darmstadt: Wittich, 1917.; Vetter, Karl. Der Zusammenbruch der Westfront. Ludendorff ist Schuld! Die Anklage der Feldgrauen. Berlin: Koch & Jurgens, 1919.; Falkenhayn, Erich. Der Feldzug Der 9. Armee Gegen Die Rumanen Und Russen, 1916/17. Berlin: E.S. Mittler & sohn, 1921. (Box-folder 15/5)
- Germany - Military: Campaigns/Battles (in German), undated; Die Neue Britische Offensive. n.d. (pictures of prisoners captured by the Germans) (Box OS 43)
- Germany - Military: Chemical Warfare (in English), 1920; Major Lefebure. The Riddle of the Rhine. 1920. (Box-folder 15/6)
- Germany - Military: Christmas at the front (in German), 1915-1917; Schleicher, Josef. Mit Weihnachtsliebesgaben ins Feindesland zu unseren Truppen 6. bis 21. Dezember 1914; Vortrag bei der in Villingen um 31. Januar 1915 abgehaltenen "Vatterlandischen Veraustaltung". 1915.; Kriegsweihnachten 1915: Grosses Hauptquartier. [s. l.]: [s. n.], 1915.; Ein Brief aus der Heimat. (title translates as "A letter from home" addressed to "Dear Comrades"); Roemer, Christian. Weihnachtsgruss in die Ferne. 1916.; Heffter, Lothar. Weihnachtsbrief des Prorektors der Alberto-Ludoviciana zu Freiburg im Breisgau an die Kommilitonen im Felde. Freiburg i. Br: [s. n.], 1917.; Müller-Hickler, Hans. Festschrift Weihnachten 1915: Dem II. Bat. Leibgarde-Inf.-Rgts No 115 gewidmet. (Darmstadt: Herbert), 1916. (fragile) (Box-folder 15/7)
- Germany - Military: Hospitals (in German), 1915; Das Kriegslazarett II. Armeekorps sechs Wochen in Franzosischer Gefangenschaft. 1915. (Box-folder 15/8)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in English), 1915-1916; Germany's Methods of Naval Warfare. London: Darling and son, limited, 1915.; Tirpitz, Wilhelm. Reichsgesetzblatt 1915, No. 49: Ordinance Relative to Amendments of the Prize Ordinance of September 30, 1909. 1915.; War-Chronicle: February 1916. 1916.; Germany. German White Book on Armed Merchantmen, With Facsimiles of the Secret Orders of the British Admiralty. 1916. (Box-folder 15/9)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in German), 1910 and undated; Englands vergeblicher Riesenkampf um die deutsche U-Boot-Basis. Berlin: K. Curtius, n. d.; Der Weltkrieg zur See: Die englische Kriegsflotte 1915. n.d.; Konnen die U.-Boote Englands Niederlage bewirken? S.l: s.n, 1910. (Box-folder 15/10)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in German), 1916; Kirchhoff, D., and Adolf Marcuse. Deutsche Kraft: U-boot und luftboot. Berlin: A. Collignon, 1916. (2 copies) (Box-folder 15/11)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in German), 1917; Thomsen, Aug. von. Die Deutsche Flotte: Eine Plauderei, Den jungen Rameraden von heer und flotte. Munchen: J. F. Lehmanns, 1917.; Wann kommt der Friede?: Die Wirkungen d. U-Bootkrieges in amtlicher Darstellung. München: Militar. Verlagsanstalt, 1917.; Wirkung und aussichten des U-bootskrieges; vortrag gehalten im auftrage des chefs des Admiralstabes der marine. Berlin: Kriegspresseamt, 1917.; Stosch, Richard von. "Volldampf voraus!": Auswahl d. wichtigsten neueren Marine-Literatur speziell der Seekriegs- u. U-Boots Literatur. Leipzig: Barsortiments-Katalog-Verl, 1917.; Kaegbein, August, and R. E. Mayr. U-Boot-Krieg und Frachtraumnot. Kriegswirtschaftliche Berichte aus dem Seminar fur Nationalokonomie und Kolonialpolitik, Hamburg /hrsg. und bearb. von Aug. Kaegbein, Folge 2. 1917. (U-boat war and shortage of cargo space); Haltung des Prasidenten der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika zur deutschen Seekriegfuhrung. Berlin: Admiralstab der Marine, 1917 (Box-folder 15/12)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in German), 1918; Wrede. Drei Jahre Seekrieg: Vortrag gehalten im Hamburger Volkshei. Hamburg: Boysen, 1918. (fragile); Bon-Ed. Karl. Die Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika und der U-Boot-Krieg. Berlin: Karl Siegismund, 1918.; Persius, Lothar. Tirpitz, der Totengraber der deutschen Flotte. Berlin: Koch & Jurgens, 1918. (fragile) (Box-folder 16/1)
- Germany - Military: Navalism / U-boats (in German), 1919-1933; Von der Kriegsfahrt des Hilfskreuzers Wolf 30 November 1916 bis 24 Februar 1918. 1919.; Rehder, Jacob. Die Kriegsschiffsverluste der fremden Flotten im Weltkriege 1914/18. Munchen: J.F. Lehmanns, 1933. (Box-folder 16/2)
- Germany - Military: Official War Reports (in Esperanto), 1915; Koncizaj informoj pri la okazintajoj de l'nuna milito gis la 30a de Aug. 1914. Al niaj korespondantoj. Germanaj oficialaj raportoj Esperantigitaj. 1915. (151 pages of collected dated entries/letters ranging from August 31, 1914- June 5, 1915) (Box-folder 16/3)
- Germany - Military: Personal Narratives / Correspondence (in French), 1914; Diaire de la Guerre: Lettres de Soldats en Campagne. Berlin: Berg, 1914. (periodical) (Box-folder 16/4)
- Germany - Military: Personal Narratives / Correspondence (in German), 1914-1916 and undated; Kriegstagebuch: Weihnachtsgabe des Vereins fur Handlungs-Commis von 1858. Hamburg: Theodro Rougemont, n.d.; Mohr, Heinrich. Feldbriefe. Freiburg im Breisgau: Herder, 1914.; Sellmann, Adolf. Ein lauernder Feind hinter der Front. 1916.; Hirts, Ferdinand. F. Hirts neue Kriegslesestucke: Erlebnisse und Darstellungen aus dem Jahre 1915. Breslau: Hirt, 1916. (Box-folder 16/5)